<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>BLOG_NAME</title>
 <link href="YOUR_URL/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="YOUR_URL"/>
 <updated>2013-08-16T13:00:59-05:00</updated>
 <id>BLOG_URL</id>
 <author>
   <name>BLOG_NAME</name>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>time for bikes, an urban transport revolution</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/time-for-bikes-an-urban-transport-revolution.html"/>
   <updated>2013-07-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/time-for-bikes-an-urban-transport-revolution</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 class=&quot;entry-title&quot;&gt;time for bikes, an urban transport revolution&lt;/h2&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s global population faces a daunting set of complex challenges — transportation, education, government, healthcare, and more. These problems seem obvious to many but actual solutions still illude us. When I think about transportation in America, I don’t see the fact that we are still reliant on fossil-fuel based transportation for our economic and social well being as the problem, but a consequence of a larger and more complex problem in how we live. Our food arrives via 18-wheeled truck and we arrive via SUV, even as 70% of our car trips are less than 2.0 miles [&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fastcodesign.com/1665634/infographic-of-the-day-how-bikes-can-solve-our-biggest-problems&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]. We’re fat, angry, and killing ourselves with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Western_pattern_diet&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Western Diet&lt;/a&gt; and long commutes.&amp;nbsp;Americans are increasingly moving to cities and we are all driving less [&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/05/14/us/report-finds-americans-are-driving-less-led-by-youth.html?pagewanted=all&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;], yet there has been no real social change in the way people feel and talk about driving, car ownership, and our love/love relationship with gasoline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our addiction to car-life influences &lt;strong&gt;everything.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Strip malls? Urban sprawl? Lack of public transportation? Crappy bike lanes? Meh bike rental and bike share programs? All a consequence of king-car, we love them more than pretty much anything else. If you live in a world where it is possible to have everything you need in a 2.0 mile radius, why would you choose to live somewhere that you have to drive 10-15 minutes to get those same things? It just doesn’t make sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But it’s hard to move! I have a job and a house!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, but living in suburbia and driving your car an hour each way is also killing you&lt;a title=&quot;Ride a bike, your commute is killing you&quot; href=&quot;http://www.livescience.com/20147-commuting-bad.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; – not to mention the rest of us. Your call, but you should probably just move before you get too old to drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Die, Sprawl, Die.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;I recently started living a car-free life, not because I’m some hippie (sorta), but actually because my car was totalled in an accident. &amp;nbsp; So it wasn’t really an active choice, although I didn’t fight the transition, I just decided not to get another car. &amp;nbsp;I now commute primarily via bicycle. I’ve become convinced that bike riding can solve all of our transportation problems. As more of America’s cities achieve population density, an urban population without cars is entirely possible. If we’re going to make this transition, we need to embrace another form of transportation — the bike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter  wp-image-562&quot; title=&quot;Don&#39;t Crash Your Car - Rent a Bike&quot; alt=&quot;Don&#39;t Crash Your Car - Rent a Bike&quot; src=&quot;http://natemcguire.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/photo-300x74.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;148&quot; scale=&quot;0&quot;&gt; “Ouch.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some naysayers will tell you it’s too hot to bike to work or that cars offer freedom not found elsewhere. Bullshit. Cars trap you and suck your soul (and wallet) while you angrily curse at that stupid person who doesn’t know how to drive. Increased stress hormones and exactly what you need – another hour in a sitting position each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s time to change how you live, get out of your car and onto a bike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But I don’t live in an urban utopia such as you have described!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then move. Come to Austin, everyone else is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Global Urbanism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you didn’t know, there were 2.1 Billion internet users at the end of 2012, or 29% of the global population.(1) Another way to look at that is: 70% of the people alive today are about to get their first broadband connection. That’s 5 Billion people who have yet to send their first Tweet, not to mention the billions that will be moving into cities in the next decade.&amp;nbsp; There is still explosive growth necessary to connect us all together, and it will only amplify our combined global issues. I believe there is a way forward, but we need to prepare for this change, together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Be a Bike Rider&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the accident, I was car-less, but not without transportation. The next day I caught the bus into downtown Austin to &lt;a href=&quot;http://capitalfactory.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Capital Factory&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and that 11-minute stop to stop trip became my norm for the next month. I also signed up for Car2go, the service that allows you to rent smart cars by the minute for point to point trips (no round-trip required).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a surprisingly smooth insurance process, I decided that rather than get a new car, I would become a bike rider instead. &amp;nbsp;Austin is full of trails and bike lanes, and I already have friends who ride their bikes to work, so I knew what I needed to get to get started. A solid commuter bike, enough gears for hilly Austin, with a rack and saddle bag for my computer. I also purchased lights (headlight and taillight) for those late nights coming home from downtown. &amp;nbsp;I ended up with a pretty good setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://natemcguire.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/2013-06-01-18.24.16.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[552]&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter  wp-image-561&quot; title=&quot;The Future of Bikes, my Fairdale - Austin Bike Rental&quot; alt=&quot;Try renting a bike&quot; src=&quot;http://natemcguire.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/2013-06-01-18.24.16-300x225.jpg&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;337.5&quot; scale=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve had my bike for over a month now and love it. I’m relying mostly on my Austin designed &lt;a title=&quot;Rent Bikes in Austin&quot; href=&quot;http://fairdalebikes.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fairdale&lt;/a&gt; bike for transport and commuting to work, with bus and car2go on the side, although I still haven’t completed a grocery store trip without a car. I generally hate traffic and think cities should be completely car free, which may not be the norm. Everyone should try bike riding, just rent a bike for a day. Hell, if you’re in Austin, rent a bike from me. You’d be surprised how far you can get in your city on a bike during your typical workday. In 2012, Over 70% of American’s car trips were less than 2 miles (3). Portland is one of the United States’ most bike-friendly cities, but it doesn’t even compare to the numbers from&amp;nbsp;Amsterdam. The &lt;a href=&quot;www.nytimes.com/2013/06/21/world/europe/a-sea-of-bikes-swamps-amsterdam-a-city-fond-of-pedaling.html?=hp&amp;amp;_r=6&amp;amp;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NYTimes reports&lt;/a&gt;, reports there are&amp;nbsp;800,000 residents, approximately 880,000 bikes. What would Austin be like with no cars and more than 1 bike for every resident? I like the sound of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How can we get started?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Americans increasingly move to cities in search of jobs, good education, healthcare, and educational opportunities our urban core will continue to grow. &amp;nbsp;We should make the transition to city life as easy as possible by encouraging the use of public transportation, ride-sharing technology, electric vehicles, and most of all, bikes. This means making biking not only the easiest form of alternative transportation, but the easiest form of transport, period. Sometimes people forget what riding a bike is like, and how much fun it can be. Maybe you’re a little like me, maybe you just need a little jolt to get them started and back in the saddle. It’s time to get out of your car and wake up to a world where you don’t have to sit in traffic every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you just have to get started. We may not be able to solve the entire world’s problems through bike riding, but it would be a start. A start towards a car-free, fossil-fuel free, sustainable world for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, who would rather sit in traffic when you could be a bike rider?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—–&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1) http://mobithinking.com/mobile-marketing-tools/latest-mobile-stats/b&lt;br&gt;
(2) http://www.ted.com/talks/jill_tarter_s_call_to_join_the_seti_search.html&lt;br&gt;
(3) http://www.fastcodesign.com/1665634/infographic-of-the-day-how-bikes-can-solve-our-biggest-problems&lt;br&gt;
(4) http://www.livescience.com/20147-commuting-bad.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resources:&lt;br&gt;
(5) http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3261937/ -&amp;nbsp;”Air Quality and Exercise-Related Health Benefits from Reduced Car Travel in the Midwestern United States”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Changes for Developers in iOS7 from Apple’s WWDC</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/changes-for-developers-in-ios7-from-apple-s-wwdc.html"/>
   <updated>2013-07-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/changes-for-developers-in-ios7-from-apple-s-wwdc</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 class=&quot;entry-title&quot;&gt;Changes for Developers in iOS7 from Apple’s WWDC&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, the 2013&amp;nbsp;&lt;a title=&quot;Apple Developer iOS7&quot; href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/wwdc/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Apple WWDC&lt;/a&gt; event had quite a few announcements, notably the changes in iOS7 for iOS app developers. &amp;nbsp;There are significant changes in overall vision of iOS, from design to how developers build their apps for iOS7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple released a full developer transition guide for Apple Developers (available if you have an account). After reading the document, I have to say that there are some impactful changes, mostly for the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;iOS 7 introduces many UI changes, such as borderless buttons, translucent bars, and full-screen layout for view controllers. Using Xcode 5, you can build a project for iOS 7 and run it in iOS 7 Simulator to get a first glimpse of the way the app looks with iOS 7 UI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-549 aligncenter&quot; title=&quot;iOS7 Changes for Developers&quot; alt=&quot;iOS7-CHANGES-FOR-DEVELOPERS&quot; src=&quot;http://natemcguire.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/iOS7-CHANGES-FOR-DEVELOPERS.png&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;398&quot; scale=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple thinks that when you start using iOS7, a few things will become clear about the main purpose and vision of the new iOS version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deference. The UI helps users understand and interact with the content, but never competes with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clarity. Text is legible at every size, icons are precise and lucid, adornments are subtle and appropriate,&amp;nbsp;and a sharpened focus on functionality motivates the design.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Depth. Visual layers and realistic motion heighten users’ delight and understanding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the smartphone and app era matures, we’re seeing a push towards simplicity with a goal of reducing noise. I strongly believe the future of technology lies in “natural” tech — technology and products designed to improve our lives that fit in as a natural part of our environment. This can be applied to small wearable technology, like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fitbit.com/flex&quot;&gt;Fitbit&lt;/a&gt;, or an extremely simple UI design that gets out of the way, like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.moves-app.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Moves&lt;/a&gt; app. You can go back and forth over design aesthetics in the new iOS version but I will never argue with a push towards simplicity and ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iOS7 also introduces dynamic type, which resizes text throughout iOS based on user preferences. This should make text appear more natural and be easier to read for each individual user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_550&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; style=&quot;width: 510px&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-550&quot; title=&quot;iOS7 Dynamic Type Example&quot; alt=&quot;iOS7-DYNAMIC-TYPE&quot; src=&quot;http://natemcguire.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/iOS7-DYNAMIC-TYPE.png&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;377&quot; scale=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;iOS7 Dynamic Type Example&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Automatic adjustments to weight, letter spacing, and line height for every font size.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ability to specify different text styles for semantically distinct blocks of text, such as Body, Footnote, or Headline1.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Text that responds appropriately to changes in both the Dynamic Type and accessibility settings for user-specified text sizes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Issues for developers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The changes in iOS7 will impact existing applications the most, especially those apps that rely heavily on the system-based templates for the application UI. This would include any app that relies on system styled buttons, navigation bars, and UI buttons. If your application uses these elements, when users upgrade to iOS7, they will see the new iOS7 buttons with the framework you intended for use in iOS6. This is obviously not great for existing apps – you will have to test your app on iOS7 and likely maintain a separate version for iOS6 in your development tree. If you need to maintain multiple versions of an app, Apple’s Xcode 5&amp;nbsp;&lt;a title=&quot;Apple iOS6 and iOS7 parallel support by Xcode5 &quot; href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/prerelease/ios/documentation/UserExperience/Conceptual/TransitionGuide/SupportingEarlieriOS.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40013174-CH14-SW1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;allows developers&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to manage multiple versions of an app in addition to allowing you to compare the differences using Apple’s Auto Layout. A primary example of an app that will need some updating is&amp;nbsp;Facebook’s mobile application. Their app relies heavily on default system buttons for some of its actions, and on iOS7 the system styled elements look completely out of place in the older framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;iOS7 Button Containers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have built an iOS app before from scratch, you’ll know that programming in Cocoa to build iOS apps involves learning about a few iOS idiosyncrasies, to say the least. Well, another big change that will affect nearly every app – Apple has removed the concept of a button container, so your application buttons are now&lt;em&gt; only text&lt;/em&gt;. Basically iOS7 would consider the container (and custom code and design) around your ‘Back’ button in the navigation irrelevant. This is a big change because most apps are using either custom code or background images to create buttons in the navigation and they will now look completely out of place on the new version of iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re in the middle of the icon design process for &lt;a title=&quot;Recipeas App - We tell you what to cook with what you have.&quot; href=&quot;http://recipeasapp.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Recipeas&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and there are a few things worth noting from a design and aesthetic perspective. Apple decided to change the&amp;nbsp;radii of the icon corners on iOS7, they’re now 12pt as opposed to iOS6′s 10pt corners. Any icons based on one iOS will end up looking bad on the other.&amp;nbsp;Love it or hate it, iOS7 is on its way to us, and more importantly our users. To make sure your app is iOS7 ready, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/prerelease/ios/documentation/UserExperience/Conceptual/TransitionGuide/TransitionGuide.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Apple recommends&lt;/a&gt; every app review this “to do” list before launching your app for iOS7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Things Every App Should Do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure that app content is discernible through translucent UI elements—such as bars and keyboards—and the transparent status bar. In iOS 7, view controllers use full-screen layout (to learn more, see “&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/prerelease/ios/documentation/UserExperience/Conceptual/TransitionGuide/AppearanceCustomization.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40013174-CH15-SW2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Using View Controllers&lt;/a&gt;”).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redesign custom bar button icons. In iOS 7, bar button icons are lighter in weight and have a different style.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare for borderless buttons by moving away from supplying button background images and by reassessing your layout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Examine your app for hard-coded UI values—such as sizes and positions—and replace them with those you derive dynamically from system-provided values. Use Auto Layout to help your app respond when layout changes are required. (If you’re new to Auto Layout, learn about it by reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/prerelease/ios/documentation/UserExperience/Conceptual/AutolayoutPG/Articles/Introduction.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40010853&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cocoa Auto Layout Guide&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Examine your app for places where the metrics and style changes of UIKit controls and views affect the layout and appearance. For example, switches are wider, grouped tables are no longer inset, and progress views are thinner. For more information on specific UI elements, see “&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/prerelease/ios/documentation/UserExperience/Conceptual/TransitionGuide/Bars.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40013174-CH8-SW1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bars and Bar Buttons&lt;/a&gt;”, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/prerelease/ios/documentation/UserExperience/Conceptual/TransitionGuide/Controls.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40013174-CH9-SW1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Controls&lt;/a&gt;”, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/prerelease/ios/documentation/UserExperience/Conceptual/TransitionGuide/ContentViews.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40013174-CH10-SW1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Content Views&lt;/a&gt;”, and “&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/prerelease/ios/documentation/UserExperience/Conceptual/TransitionGuide/TempViews.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40013174-CH11-SW1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Temporary Views&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scope the Project: Adopt Dynamic Type. In iOS 7, users can adjust the text size they see in apps. When you adopt Dynamic Type, you get text that responds appropriately to user-specified size changes. For more information, see “&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/prerelease/ios/documentation/UserExperience/Conceptual/TransitionGuide/AppearanceCustomization.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40013174-CH15-SW4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Using Fonts&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure your app doesn’t respond inappropriately to the new Control Center gesture or to a navigation contoller’s swipe to go back gesture, especially if you perform custom touch handling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revisit the use of drop shadows, gradients, and bezels. Because the iOS 7 aesthetic is smooth and layered—with much less emphasis on using visual effects to make UI elements look physical—you may want to rethink these effects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If necessary, update your app to best practices for iOS 6—such as Auto Layout and storyboards—and ensure that the app uses no deprecated API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>